REBECCA RHOADS

945 S Ridge Road, Denver PA 17517 · 717.201.2183

Cbrhoads5@gmail.com

After graduating college in 1998, I was employed as a counselor at a partial hospital school. I worked with students that were experiencing a wide range of emotional and psychological stressors. The work was challenging and yet rewarding. I stepped away from the demands of working to raise a family. During this time, I experienced parenting first hand. It is the most difficult job out there. Each of my children developed differently and at their own pace. Each personality added to and completed our family. Experiencing the sibling dynamics and circumventing everyday life as a parent taught me that each child and family has different needs and making each need flow in a family dynamic is key to emotional stability and function. As they reached teenage years, I craved work with children again. Due to being out of the workforce for such a long period of time, I decided to re-enter and re-introduce myself to the current education systems and needs. I became a substitute teacher for several school districts. I taught in several AS, ES, and Life Skills classrooms. The students were remarkable. As a substitute I often found myself on the periphery of the teaching plan. Supervisors, teachers, and paraprofessionals taught me a lot about positive reinforcement and how to apply preferred objects to increase a behavior I observed and learned informally at every opportunity. I wanted to expand my knowledge and capabilities of learning Applied Behavior Analysis. I enrolled and graduated from University of Cincinnati's Master of Education with Foundations in Applied Behavior Analysis program. I am proud to have graduated with a 4.0 cumulative average while working as a registered behavior technician for a wonderful company, I linked life experience, classroom experience, and formal education in Applied Behavior Analysis together and to be a conduit for students and families to excel. I enjoy being part of a team of educators, students and families to increase potential, learning and growth. I have enjoyed working in a school setting and building relationships with staff and students. The busy and ever-changing education environment is challenging and full of opportunities for growth. I now seek to join a school team and be fully immersed in the school community.

EXPERIENCE

ABA Support Services, Nazareth PA- Board Certified Behavior Analyst September 2023-Present

september 2020-i 1ese

- IBHS caseload
- School based BCBA across high school, middle school and elementary schools
 - Collaboration with teachers, MTSS team members and administration
 - Conduct FBAs
 - Record reviews
 - Indirect interviews and assessments with parents, teachers and case managers
 - Direct observations with ABC data collection
 - Functional hypotheses provided

- Goal recommendations paired with a comprehensive individualized Positive Behavior Support Plan
- Participation in IEP meetings
 - Write and present behavioral goals
- Member of an inclusion team working to transition a student from out of district placement back to the home district
- Observations for students and classrooms demonstrating behaviors interfering with the learning environment,
 - Tier 1 and 2 interventions provided for the teacher
- Direct support with students
- Coach teachers, paraprofessionals and support staff on interventions
- Provided staff development trainings on ABA principles and classroom management
- Development of crisis plans

ABA Support Services, Nazareth PA-Licensed Behavior Specialist

February 2022-September 2023

- Supervisor for IBHS caseload up to 11 clients
 - Individualized treatment plans with behavior intervention plans
 - Behavior assessments
 - Individualized programming based on client needs
 - Worked within home, daycare, and schools
 - Collaboration with school teams, health professionals and families

ABA Support Services, Nazareth PA- Registered Behavior Technician

July 2020-February 2022

- Registered with BACB
- Collaborative work with BCBA and treatment team to write treatment plans
- Progress reports
- Collection of data on rate, frequency and average
- Implementation of behavioral interventions
- Use of positive reinforcement

VIPKID Incorporated, San Francisco CA- ESL Teacher, Practiced in PA only

October 2017-April 2021

- English immersion classes with students throughout China
- 495 students, 3979 classes completed
- Excellent parent feedback
- Shifts begin from 1-3 am
- Independent preparation for classes
- Intercultural communication with parents and students
- Total Physical Response (TPR)
- Implementation of visual aides and creative learning to help understand new concepts and vocabulary
- Assessment of learned skills

The Substitute Teacher Service, Lancaster PA-Substitute Teacher

October 2015-July 2020

- Implementing teacher's current lesson plans to provide a consistent venue of learning
- Many repeat classrooms

- Variety of races, backgrounds, and cultures
- Autistic Support classrooms
- Emotional Support classrooms
- Life Skills classrooms
- General Education

Stay at Home Mom, PA

February 2002-October 2015

Kids Peace, Temple PA-Counselor Support

March 1999-February 2002

- Counselor support in an educational setting
- Behavior goals
- Students from kindergarten to 12th grade
- Crisis intervention

Kids Peace, Bethlehem PA- After School Counseling Program

June 1998-March 1999

- Charting of progress
- Focus group implementation

Pepperidge Farms, Denver PA

June 1997-June 1998

- Fast paced environment
- Office work such as filing
- Reading and recording trucking invoices for shipping and receiving

EDUCATION

University of Cincinnati, Cincinnati OH/ MEd with foundations in Applied Behavior Analysis, Online Courses taken from PA only

May 2020-December 2021

• 4.0 GPA

Kutztown University, Kutztown PA/ B.S. Psychology

September 1996-December 1998

- 3.2 GPA
- Dean's List Fall 1997

Elizabethtown College, Elizabethtown PA

September 1994-May 1996

Women's Soccer Team

CERTIFICATIONS

- Board Certified Behavior Analyst
- Pennsylvania Licensed Behavior Specialist

- PaTTAN Basic Intensive Skill Training in Appled Behavior Analysis for Teams Serving Students with Autism 07/2022
- Current Safety Care certification
- All required background checks and clearances for the school setting

SKILLS

- Knowledge of lesson plans and classroom settings
- Adaptive to a vast number of setting situations, strategic teaching techniques and behavioral interventions
- Capable organizer and independent problem solver
- Cultural awareness of students
- Online classroom experience
- Excellent communication skills
- Able to quickly form solid rapport with clients, families, therapists and educators
- Abie to work under time constraints and change tactics quickly
- Proactive approach to problem solving